Preliminary Guide to the Fred John Beck Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Fred John Beck papers
1928-1971
MS 681
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
15.75
(17 boxes)
The papers consist of departmental files, course notes, problems, examinations, student papers, correspondence, and student grade books, all relating to Fred Beck's teaching career at Yale University. In addition there is a small amount of material on his teaching elsewhere (ca. 1940-1945), texts of public lectures, grant materials, and miscellaneous writings.
Beck, Fred John
Conditions Governing Access
Student grades contained in Box 9 are restricted until January 1, 2046 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series: I. Departmental Files. II. Subject Files. III. Student Papers and Student Correspondence. IV. Student Grade Books and Other Materials Relating to Grades. V. Course Notes. VI. Problems and Exams.
Scope and Contents
The Fred Beck Papers (17 boxes) have thus far been divided only into very general series; there has been no attempt made to arrange the material within each series. The only exceptions to this are the COURSE/NOTES and the PROBLEMS and EXAMS series, which have been arranged very roughly by course numbers. For related papers see also YRGs [23, 31, and 14].
Biographical / Historical
Fred John Beck (1904-\): E.E., Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1925; Ph.D., Yale University, 1932; instructor, Electrical Engineering, Yale University, 1928-1936, assistant professor, 1936-1942, associate professor, 1942-1953, professor, 1953-1963, professor of Engineering and Applied Science, 1963-.
Engineering; Educators; Engineers; Beck, Fred John; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Dept. of Electrical Engineering
- Department Files, Circa 1950s-1971; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains minutes of various departmental and university committee meetings, and inner- and inter-departmental memos, form letters, and bulletins. Most of this material falls between 1965 and 1971, but some dates back to the 1950s. Also included in this series are: correspondence in reference to Sigma Chi, a science honorary fraternity; correspondence about departmental matters in general; the upkeep of the physical plant at the Engineering School; material about the Honeywell award; bursary material; Yale Studies for Returning Servicemen; miscellaneous topics similar to those listed above.
  - Departmental Files, Circa 1950s-1971 (Box 1)
  - Departmental Files, Circa 1950s-1971 (Box 2)
  - Departmental Files, Circa 1950s-1971 (Box 3)
- Subject Files, Circa 1940s-1950s; Series II
  Included in this series are: notes for course Beck taught elsewhere (New Haven YMCA Junior College, ca. 1940-1945), honorary and public lectures by Beck; writings by Beck and others, material on the American Institute of Electrical Engineers; various grants and consulting jobs by Beck; topics of general interest to Beck. This material, unlike Series I, primarily seems to be from the 1940s and 1950s.
  - Subject Files, Circa 1940s-1950s (Box 4)
  - Subject Files, Circa 1940s-1950s (Box 5)
  - Subject Files, Circa 1940s-1950s (Box 6)
- Student Papers and Student Correspondence, Series III
  This series, for the most part, consists of laboratory report books, copies of senior projects and Ph.D. dissertations. There also are some miscellaneous papers for various classes, published papers by former students, letters from several students discussing their dissertation progress, and ideas and problems that they are facing.
  - Student Papers and Student Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Student Papers and Student Correspondence (Box 8)
- Student Grade Books and Material Relating to Grades, Circa 1928-1970; Series IV
  This series consists of approximately 90 grade books from [1928-1929]-1970. Books which have no dates in them have been kept in the same order as Professor Beck had them. There are also 11 folders of grade lists and other materials related to grades. This includes a folder describing Ph.D dissertation requirements, as well as sample syllabi.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Student grades are restricted until January 1, 2046 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
  - Student Grade Books and Material Relating to Grades, Circa 1928-1970 (Box 9)
- Course Notes, Series V
  This series contains course and lecture notes, as well as problem sheets, for courses Beck taught at Yale. This material has been grouped by couse number. Box 12 contains miscellaneous course material.
  - Course Notes (Box 10)
  - Course Notes (Box 11)
  - Course Notes (Box 12)
- Problems and Exams, Series VI
  This series consists of mimeographed copies of engineering problems used in classes and examinations for the various courses. The material is arranged by course number.
  - EE30 and EE40 (Box 13)
  - EE103, EE21, EE114 (Box 14)
  - EE H2, EE116, EE140, EE200, EE201, EE240, EE250 (Box 15)
  - EE1, EE23, EE31, EE35 (also miscellaneous and unidentified) (Box 16)
  - Problem books (loose leaf) for various courses (Box 17)